（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
Despite being relatively unknown
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       ninjacloud
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（火神(かがみ)）くっ この野郎…
Seriously, this guy...
I can't get past him.
マジでこいつ… 抜けねえ！
（黒子(くろこ)）あっ
No! Don't do it, Kagami!
（日向(ひゅうが)）ダメだ 行くな火神！
（津川(つがわ)）うっ
Offensive foul!
（審判）オフェンスファウル！
白10番！
White 10!
Quit running your mouth, you braggart.
（日向）
ガタガタうるせぇぞ 茶坊主が
（日向）今からオマエに
先輩への口のきき方 教えてやる
I'm going to teach you how to properly talk to your seniors.
（伊月(いづき)）ふっ…
Seirin benched their first years.
（高尾(たかお)）誠凛(せいりん)１年コンビ
引っ込めちまったぞ
No,
（緑間(みどりま)）いや… むしろ逆だ
they're doing just the opposite.
They intend to...
あの目は…
But I can't just sit still!
だからってジッとしてらんねーよ！
４ファウルの人は
すっこんでください
Guys with four fouls should stay on the bench.
Seirin.................................................Seiho
Seirin, member change.
（オフィシャル）誠凛
メンバーチェンジです
Seirin.................................................Seiho
（津川）あっ なんだー 君だけ？
It's just you?
オレ 火神と
やりたかったんだけどなー
I wanted to play against Kagami.
（黒子）すみません
力不足かもしれませんが—
Sorry, I may not be very strong,
借りがあるそうなんで
返しに来ました
but he apparently has a grudge, and I'm here to pay it back.
代理で
By proxy.
フフフッ 火神の借りを？
You're paying me back in place of Kagami?
大室(おおむろ)さん マーク代わって
もらえないですか
Omuro, could I change my mark?
Huh? Why?
（大室）ああ？ なんでだよ
いや〜 なんか代理人が
返済に来たらしいんで
Well...
It seems I've got a proxy here demanding attention.
Episode 10
I Can't Have That
Seirin...................................................................Seiho
I'm surprised they sent you and not Kagami out,
（津川）火神が出ないで—
君だけってのは
ビックリしたけど
結局 １年生出て来るなんて
but for them to send a first year at all...
Looks like Seirin's upperclassmen aren't so dependable.
やっぱ 誠凛の先輩たちって
ちょっと頼りないね
だって君ら２人引っ込めたのは
先輩の意地だってさっき言ってたよ
They just said they benched you two because it was their will.
But here you are.
で 今 君いんじゃん
出してほしいと言ったのは
ボクのほうです
I asked to be put in.
Anyway, if you've been watching the game,
そもそも
今までの試合ぶりを見て—
there's no way you could believe that.
そんなこと思えるはずないです
先輩には先輩の意地があるなら
後輩には後輩の敬意があります
If the upperclassmen have their will,
then lowerclassmen have their respect.
尊敬する先輩を支えるためにも—
I will defeat you to support the upperclassmen
that I respect.
ボクは君を倒します
ふーん
ぐうっ
（津川）見失った… なんで！？
今 いつの間に！？
I lost him! How did...? When did he?
でやっ
（観客１）うぉぉ また来た！
（観客２）誠凛の魔法のパス！
There it is again!
Seirin's magic pass!
（岩村(いわむら)）ああ…
どうなってる！？
確かにあのパスは脅威だ
What's going on?
Those passes are dangerous.
が もらうほうもディフェンスを
かわせるようになってきている
But...
Even the other players are slipping past the defense!
What?!
何だと？
（岩村）パスカット！
A steal!
Could they be...
まさか こいつら…
What is this?
何だよ… 何だよ コレ！
What's going on?!
They've seen through our movements!
ウチの動きを完全にとらえてる
They got us good.
（松元(まつもと)）やられたぜ
I've never seen anyone study us so thoroughly before.
ここまでウチを研究して来たトコは
初めてだわ
おかげさまで ＤＶＤデッキ１個
オシャカにしたんで…
Thanks to you guys, one of our DVD players is ruined.
They really got us.
（春日(かすが)）まいったね どーも
（笠松(かさまつ)）古武術ってのは
その名の通りいにしえの技
As their name suggests, old martial arts techniques are ancient.
Their thought process is completely different from modern sports science.
（笠松）現代のスポーツ科学とは
考え方がまったく違う
Applying those specialized movements to basketball is Seiho's strength,
それをバスケに応用した
特殊な動きが正邦の強さだ が
but...
If you're specialized, you've got habits.
（リコ）特殊ってことは
クセがあるってこと
For example, people usually step towards the direction they're heading as they start to move.
普通は動き出すのと同時に
移動する方向に足を出す
正邦の選手は 既に
爪先を移動する方向に向けている
Seiho's players point their toes in the direction they're heading before they even move.
In other words, once we recognize that habit,
つまり そのクセさえ見抜けば
次の動作を予測できるってこと
we can predict their next move.
だから練習の後
２年生だけで研究を重ねてきた
That's why the second years have been studying hard on their own after practice.
（リコ）とはいえ
あの動きについていくのは—
That said, keeping up with those movements was harder than we expected.
予想以上にしんどかったわ
Because of that, we haven't been able to deal with them until the second half.
（日向）おかげで
対応できるようになったのは—
後半になってからだけどな
It's not really obvious enough to be called a habit.
（伊月）実際クセって言うほど
あからさまじゃねーし
（伊月）クセに苦戦
（土田(つちだ)）だよな
Habits are hard to beat.
I know, right?
１本！
One!
これが… 先輩の意地
This is the will of my seniors...
Now that I think about it,
（火神）そういえばベンチから
黒子を見るの初めてだな…
this is the first time I've watched Kuroko play from the bench.
すげえ
Amazing...
You just noticed? He's always like this!
何 今頃言ってんのよ
いつもこんなもんよ！
Seirin.................................................................Seiho
A comeback? Is Seirin for real?
（観客１）逆転！？ マジか誠凛
（観客２）追いついた…
Seirin.................................................................Seiho
They caught up!
けど…
But...
We can't let them get this!
ここは絶対とられるわけには
いかねーぞ！
Do not underestimate a king!
王者をなめるなよ！
貴様らごときが勝つのは10年早い！
You need 10 more years of experience to beat us!
（リコ）
オールコートマンツーマン！？
All court man-to-man?
守るどころか
もう１ゴール取る気だ
They're not just trying to defend,
they're trying to score again!
まだまだぁ
This isn't over yet!
How can they try so hard in the final seconds?
（伊月）この土壇場で
そのマジっぷりは どんだけだよ
ナイス！ 見とれちゃうぜ 水戸部(みとべ)
Nice!
I'm impressed, Mitobe!
Damn it!
しまった！
Tsugawa? How?
津川！？ なんで…
He found him by calculating backwards from the pass' target!
パスコースから逆算して
察知したんだ
黒子ォォォォ！！
Kuroko!
He missed?
（津川）スルー！？
このタイミングで まさか…
With this timing, there's no way he could change his target.
パスターゲットを変えられるわけ…
Seirin
Seiho
（誠凛選手たち）よっしゃー
（審判）試合終了
Yes!
Game over!
Seirin..................................................................Seiho
（１年生たち）よっしゃー
（小金井(こがねい)）よっしゃー やったー！
All right!
We did it!
オマエら よくやったな
You were amazing!
We won!
よくやったな 黒子
You really showed them, Kuroko.
We lost.
負けた
（津川）な… なんでだよ！
Why?!
誠凛なんて
去年できたばかりのところだろ！？
Seirin just formed last year!
We practice way more than them!
練習だって
絶対ウチのほうがしてるのに！
They didn't stand a chance last year!
去年なんて
相手にもならなかったのに！
No matter how you look at it, we're stronger!
強いのは… 強いのは
どう考えてもウチじゃん！
Enough, Tsugawa.
（岩村）やめろ 津川
But...
だって…
強いほうが勝つんじゃねぇ
勝ったほうが強いんだ
The strong don't win.
The winners are the strong ones.
They were stronger.
あいつらのほうが強かった
それだけだ
That's all.
Tell me your name!
（津川）名前教えてよ！
（黒子）え？
Your name!
名前
黒子テツヤです
It's Kuroko Tetsuya.
I'll remember it.
覚えとく 絶対 忘れないからな！
I definitely won't forget.
Thanks.
どうも…
73-71, Seirin!
（審判）73対71 誠凛！
Thank you very much!
（選手たち）
ありがとうございました！
Congratulations, guys.
おめでとう… みんな
シャンとしろ カントク
まだ泣くところじゃねぇよ
Keep it together, Coach.
It's not time to cry yet.
You can be happy after we win the championship next.
喜ぶのは次の決戦に勝ってからだ
あっちも終わったみてーだな
Looks like they're finished too.
そうですね
You're right.
（審判）113対38 秀徳(しゅうとく)！
113-38, Shutoku!
Shutoku...................................................Ginbo
（選手たち）
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
（秀徳部員たち）お疲れ様でした
Good game!
How much do we have to love basketball
（高尾）こっから
また休憩挟んで決勝戦って—
どんだけバスケ好きなのよ オレら
to jump right into the championship game with hardly a break?
けどま よかったじゃん 来たぜ
But, well, it's all good.
They made it.
（緑間）見れば分かるのだよ
I can see that.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Go put on jackets before you cool down!
（リコ）体が冷えないように
すぐ上着着て！
Make sure you stretch!
ストレッチも入念にね
Also, take some amino acids to restore your energy!
それから疲労回復にアミノ酸！
カロリーチャージも忘れずに！
Don't forget to recharge your calories!
I'll come around and give each of you a massage, so take off your shoes!
あと順番にマッサージに行くから
バッシュ脱いでて
（リコ）どう？
（日向）サンキュ
How does that feel?
Thanks.
まあ 疲れてないって言ったら
ウソになるけど—
I'd be lying if I said I'm not tired,
これでなんとか次までは持つだろう
but I'll somehow make it through the next game.
ふん うん？
Hey, Kagami!
ちょっ コラ 火神！
寝たら体固まっちゃうでしょーが！
Your body will tighten up if you sleep!
Let him be.
（日向）まあ ほっとけよ
（リコ）え？
あいつ 珍しくへこんでいたからな
He's not usually this down after a game.
It's probably because he got four fouls.
４ファウルで抜けたからだろ？
気にすることねーのに
It's not anything to worry about.
Your last foul was a little unexpected though.
コガが最後に抜けたのは
予定外だったけどね
Maybe he feels responsible in his own way.
こいつなりに責任
感じてんじゃねーの
Besides, I don't think he's sleeping.
それにただ寝てるって言うより
He looks to me like he's saving every last bit of energy he has for the next game.
次の試合に備えて—
最後の一滴まで力を溜めて
いるように見えるからな
すみません ちょっと
トイレ行ってきます
Excuse me. I need to go to the bathroom.
あ オレも行っとこ
I'll go too.
（高尾）けどビックリだわ 実際
マジで誠凛が来るとはね
Honestly, what a surprise.
I didn't think Seirin would actually make it.
（高尾）やあ
（小金井）えっ？
Hey.
どうも
Hello.
Oh? An upperclassman?
（高尾）お？ 先輩も？
ツレションっスか〜
Are you two going to the bathroom together?
I look forward to playing you in the next game.
次の試合 よろしくでっす
Yeah, you too...
He noticed Kuroko walking behind him?
（小金井）
後ろを通る黒子に気付いた？
All right! Ten minutes left!
（大坪(おおつぼ)）よし 10分前だ！
（日向）行くぞ！
Let's go!
Midorima...
緑間
Sorry. Please go on ahead.
（緑間）すみません
先に行ってください
Kagami, it's time.
（黒子）火神君 時間です
（緑間）黒子
そしてヤツの新しい光
Kuroko, and his new light, Kagami.
火神…
シューティングをかかした日はない
I did not miss a day of shooting.
I did not slack off at practice.
練習も手を抜いたことはない
左手の爪のケアもいつも通り
My left hand nail care is as impeccable as always.
今日の占い かに座は１位
Today's horoscope for Cancer's is the best.
I even brought today's lucky item, a raccoon Shigaraki.
ラッキーアイテム
タヌキの信楽焼も持ってきている
I tied the laces on my right shoe first.
バッシュのヒモは右から結んだ
人事は尽くした！
I have done everything I can.
Let's go!
（火神）行くか！
Yes.
はい
You're late.
（高尾）おっせーよ！
The upperclassmen already left.
先輩たち 行っちまったぞ
Honestly, I don't think many believed Seirin would make it this far.
正直 ここまで
誠凛が勝ち進んでくると—
予想していた者は少ないだろう
The King of the North losing can be called nothing other than an upset.
北の王者の敗退は
番狂わせと言う他ない
だが それだけのことだ
However, it is nothing more than that.
For us, nothing changes.
ウチにとっては何も変わらん
Whether we're dealing with a tiger or a rabbit,
相手が虎であろうと
兎であろうと—
獅子のすることは１つ
there is only one thing for a lion to do.
Crush them with all our might!
全力でたたき潰すのみだ！
As usual, there is only victory!
いつも通り 勝つのみ！！
Yeah!
（一同）おう！
いや〜 疲れた！
Man, I'm beat.
今日はもう朝から憂うつでさ〜
I've been feeling in the dumps since this morning.
２試合連続だし 王者だし
We've got two games in a row, both against kings.
And even while playing Seiho,
正邦とやってるときも倒しても
もう１試合あるとか考えるし
all I could think about was playing another game after we beat them.
けどあと１試合
But there's only one game left.
もう次だの温存だの
We don't have to worry about any crap like the next game or reserving our energy.
まどろっこしいことは
いんねー
気分スッキリ
やることは１つだけ！
We can focus on the one thing we have to do!
Give it every single thing we have!
ぶっ倒れるまで
全部出しきれ！
Yeah!
（一同）おう！
Line up!
（審判）整列
（日向）思ったよりおとなしいな
He's quieter than I expected.
（緑間）まさか—
I didn't think you would actually make it this far.
本当に勝ち上がってくるとは
思わなかったのだよ
But it ends here.
だが ここまでだ
どんな弱小校や無名校でも
みんなで力を合わせれば戦える
No matter how weak, small, or unknown,
any team can fight as long as they work together.
That is nothing but an illusion.
そんなものは幻想なのだよ
Come.
来い オマエの選択がいかに愚かか
教えてやろう
I will show you just how foolish your choice was.
No one knows what the right decision is to make in life,
人生の選択で何が正しいかなんて
誰にも分かりませんし—
and that is not why I made this choice.
そんな理由で
選んだわけではないです
それに１つ反論させてもらえば
誠凛は決して弱くはありません
Also, if I may disagree with one thing,
it's that Seirin is not weak.
We will not lose.
負けません 絶対
Seirin................................................Shutoku
（笠松）誠凛が
王者連続撃破の奇跡を起こすか
Will Seirin miraculously dethrone two kings in a row and win,
or will Shutoku protect its rightful throne?
秀徳が順当に王者のイスを守るか…
（審判）
それでは予選Ａブロック決勝—
Let the A Block preliminary championship game
between Seirin High School and Shutoku High School begin!
誠凛高校 対 秀徳高校の
試合を始めます！
Thank you!
（選手たち）お願いします！
The championship game!
（笠松）さぁ 決戦だ！
あれ？
あいさつは黒子君だけでいいのかよ
Huh? Is Kuroko the only one you need to talk to?
What about Kagami?
（高尾）火神は…
（緑間）必要ない
There is no need.
あんな情けない試合をするヤツと
話すことなどないのだよ
There is no reason for me to talk to someone who played such a pathetic game.
もし 言いたいことが
あるようなら プレーで示せ
If you have anything to say, you can show it to me with your play.
Right back at you.
同感だね 思い出すたび
自分に腹が立ってしょうがねぇ
Just thinking about it makes me mad at myself.
フラストレーション
溜まりまくりだよ
I've got tons of pent up frustration, so
だから早くやろーぜ
let's do this already.
全部 闘争心に変えて
テメーを倒すために溜めてたんだ
I've turned it all into rage, and I've been saving it for you.
もう これ以上抑えらんねーよ
I can't hold it in any longer.
What did you say?
何だと？
Do your worst.
やれるものなら やってみろ
（伊月）さすが速(はえ)え！
They're quick!
We wanted to run-and-gun for a quick shot, but...
まずは速効で１本
とるつもりだったんだけど
There are no gaps in their defense.
（降旗(ふりはた)）うっわ スキねえ〜
（河原(かわはら)）１本！ 大事に！
（リコ）じゃない！
Get one! Take your time!
No!
格上相手に
のんびり合わせてたら—
Simply matching a stronger opponent is like giving them control of the game.
主導権
プレゼントするようなもんよ！
To take the first quarter
まず第１クオーターを取る！
そのためにも…
you have to...
あいさつがてらに 強襲ゴー
greet them by storm!
（大坪）うっ
（木村(きむら)）あっ あれは？
That's...
It's the same thing they did against me.
（黄瀬）オレとやったときと同じ
An alley-oop.
アリウープ
Yes, we got the first bucket!
やった 先取点！
いけぇ！
Go!
（高尾）ううっ さっすが真(しん)ちゃん
I knew you could do it, Shin.
No way.
まさか
He can block that?
（リコ）
あれをブロックしちゃうワケ？
How disappointing.
まったく 心外なのだよ
その程度で出し抜いたつもりか？
You think you can beat us with that?
（観客１）外れた！
（観客２）両チーム 譲らねぇ！
He missed!
Neither team has scored!
Seirin.........................................Shutoku
Oh, man.
あ〜らら
均衡状態に入っちゃったか〜？
They're stuck in the mud.
A basketball game is 40 minutes long.
（岩村）バスケの試合は40分
The game is broken up into four ten minute quarters.
10分ずつ４クオーターと
細かく区切られている
Basically, the flow of the game automatically resets at least three times.
それはつまり—
最低３回は流れが変わる
ポイントがあるということだ
However, in other words...
しかし 逆に言えば…
Once your opponent takes control of the game,
一度流れを持ってかれると
そのクオーター中に戻すのは困難だ
it's very difficult to take it back during the same quarter.
It's been almost two minutes and neither team has scored.
両チーム無得点のまま
もうすぐ２分
At this rate, whoever gets the first bucket
Seirin......................................Shutoku
このままいくと第１クオーターは
おそらく…
will take the first quarter!
先取点を取ったほうが取る
速攻！
To the hoop!
（日向）なっ… まさか この場面で
スリー打つつもりかよ！？ 緑間
What? Are you going to shoot a three from there?
Midorima!
（黒子）走っててください
（火神）はっ
Keep running.
（歓声）
（観客１）うわあ 来た スリー
It's a three pointer!
（観客２）なんつーシュートだ
What an incredible shot!
（観客３）先制点は 秀徳だ！
Shutoku has struck first!
Seirin.........................................Shutoku
しまった
Oh no.
（黄瀬）均衡が崩れた
（笠松）これで流れは秀徳だ！
The deadlock has been broken!
Shutoku's in control now!
（緑間）何だと？
What?
（火神）フンッ おりゃ！
They got them back in a second!
（観客１）一瞬でやり返したぞ
（観客２）すげえ！
Amazing!
Wha—
（リコ）なっ
（小金井）何なんだよ 今のは
What was that?
That cut straight from one end of the court to the other.
コートの端から端まで
ぶった切ったぞ
くっ… 黒子
Kuroko...
I'm sorry.
すみません
I can't let you take the first quarter that easily.
そう簡単に第１クオーターを
取られると困ります
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
（緑間）黒子…
Kuroko...
（高尾）正直ビビったのだよ
（緑間）ビビってないのだよ
Honestly, you scared me.
Seirin..................................Sh
I'm not scared.
（高尾）顔の横を通ったのだよ
（緑間）高尾
It passed right by my face.
Takao...
（高尾）もう少しで
当たるところだったのだよ
It almost hit me!
Episode 11
That's Not It
（緑間）マネをするな！
Don't imitate me!